<?xml version="1.0"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>jiaqili.com</title>
    <link></link>
    <atom:link href="http://http://www.jiaqili.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>RSS feed for jiaqili.com</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <pubDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 23:45:49 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Mar 2014 23:45:49 -0400</lastBuildDate>
 
    
    <item>
      <title>Businessweek Interviews Apple Execs</title>
      <link>/2013/09/19/apple-execs-businessweek.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2013 13:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><p><a href="http://www.businessweek.com/articles/2013-09-19/cook-ive-and-federighi-on-the-new-iphone-and-apples-once-and-future-strategy#r=hp-lst">Businessweek</a>:</p>




<blockquote><p>Tim Cook: &ldquo;I think [Nokia] is a reminder to everyone in business that you have to keep innovating and that to not innovate is to die.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Craig Federighi: &ldquo;New? New is easy. Right is hard.&rdquo;</p></blockquote>




<p>Good interview with Apple CEO Tim Cook, SVP of Design Jony Ive, and SVP of Software Engineering Craig Federighi.</p>

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moto X - Made in America</title>
      <link>/2013/09/14/motox-made-in-america.html</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2013 16:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-09-11/the-iphone-s-secret-flights-from-china-to-your-local-apple-store.html">The Verge</a>:</p>




<blockquote><p>Made in America: a look inside Motorola&rsquo;s Moto X factory</p>

<p>An old Nokia facility has been resurrected to crank out 100,000 new smartphones per week</p></blockquote>




<p>Although most of the components are actually manufactured in Asian and shipped to Texas, this piece offers a fascinating look inside Google/Motorola&rsquo;s smartphone factory.</p>

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>iPhone Supply Chain</title>
      <link>/2013/09/13/iphone-supply-chain.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2013 22:59:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><p><a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-09-11/the-iphone-s-secret-flights-from-china-to-your-local-apple-store.html">Bloomberg</a>:</p>




<blockquote><p>Apple first coordinates flights and trucks to move components from suppliers to assembly plants in China. Teams from sales, marketing, operations and finance collaborate to forecast how many devices the company expects to sell.</p>

<p>The internal estimate is crucial. An example of how that can go wrong is Microsoft&rsquo;s recent <a href="http://www.bloomberg.com/news/2013-07-30/microsoft-sold-853-million-in-surface-tablets.html">$900 million writedown</a> because of unsold Surface tablets.</p>

<p>Before Apple&rsquo;s formal unveiling on stage, iPhones are shipped to distribution centers around the world, including Australia, China, the Czech Republic, Japan, Singapore, the U.K. and the U.S. FedEx ships Apple handsets to the U.S. mainly using Boeing 777s&hellip; The 777s can carry about 450,000 iPhones and cost about $242,000 to charter, with fuel accounting for more than half the expense.</p></blockquote>




<p>All the more impressive because of the massive number of SKUs (stock-keeping-units) this year.</p>




<ul>
<li>iPhone 4 (still sold in China) - 2 (2 colors)</li>
<li>iPhone 4s - 2 (2 colors)</li>
<li>iPhone 5c - 50 (5 colors x 2 storage capacities x 5 LTE bands)</li>
<li>iPhone 5s - 45 (3 colors x 3 storage capacities x 5 LTE bands)</li>
</ul>




<p>Total of 99 unique iPhones to forecast and manage production/inventory.</p>

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riptide</title>
      <link>/2013/09/09/riptide.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><p><a href="http://www.niemanlab.org/riptide/">Nieman Journalism Lab</a>:</p>




<blockquote><p>An oral history of the epic collision between journalism and digital technology, from 1980 to the present featuring over 60 interviews with</p></blockquote>




<p>A fantastic, 15-chapter oral history of the collision between journalism and technology.</p>

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yahoo's New Logo</title>
      <link>/2013/09/09/yahoo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2013 22:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><p><a href="http://glog.glennf.com/blog/2013/9/6/yahoos-logo-reveals-the-worst-aspects-of-engineering-mindset">Glenn Fleishman</a>:</p>




<blockquote><p>[Marissa] Mayer clearly appreciates the expertise and insight of folks who write code at Yahoo, run the servers, handle human resources, and the like. But, apparently, sees graphic design as something she is equally qualified to participate in without domain knowledge.</p>

<p>The Yahoo logo design process represents the worst aspects of someone who doesn&rsquo;t understand or accept that type design, typography, and graphic design in general are professions that benefit from years or decades of training.</p></blockquote>




<p>Ouch. A sharply critical and very insightful piece on the new Yahoo logo.</p>

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samsung Galaxy Gear</title>
      <link>/2013/09/04/galaxy-gear.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 22:19:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/9/4/4692824/samsung-galaxy-gear-features-specs-release-date-price">The Verge</a>:</p>




<blockquote><p>Samsung promises &ldquo;about a day&rdquo; of endurance from the Gear, but by the end of our briefing with the company, the cameras on most of its demo units were refusing to turn on due to the watches running low on power.</p></blockquote>




<p>$300 for this?</p>

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nintendo</title>
      <link>/2013/09/03/nintendo.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><p><a href="http://daringfireball.net/2013/09/nintendo_in_motion" title="Daring Fireball: Nintendo in Motion">John Gruber</a>:</p>




<blockquote><p>The world has changed in the last five years, and hundreds of millions of people now carry powerful, well-made, touchscreen computers with them everywhere they go.</p></blockquote>




<p><a href="http://hypercritical.co/2013/09/02/nintendo-in-crisis" title="Hypercritical.co: Nintendo in Crisis">John Siracusa</a>:</p>




<blockquote><p>As long as there continues to be a market for devices that are primarily designed to play games, then it’s possible for Nintendo to live to fight another day.</p></blockquote>




<p>Is there a big enough market for dedicated gaming devices to sustain Nintendo?</p>

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dark Patterns</title>
      <link>/2013/08/30/dark-patterns.html</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2013 18:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/8/29/4640308/dark-patterns-inside-the-interfaces-designed-to-trick-you">The Verge</a>:</p>




<blockquote><p>A dark pattern is a user interface carefully crafted to trick users into doing things they might not otherwise do, such as buying insurance with their purchase or signing up for recurring bills.</p></blockquote>




<p>Some of this is bad design, some of it is intentional.</p>

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do Scalpers Exist?</title>
      <link>/2013/08/28/why-do-scalpers-exist.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 22:46:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><p><a href="http://priceonomics.com/why-do-scalpers-exist/">Priceonomics</a>:</p>




<blockquote><p>When there is excess demand for a new car or phone, some people might sell theirs at a markup on eBay, but there’s nobody across the street from the dealership or Best Buy offering it right away for double the sticker price&hellip;</p>

<p>Yet concerts and sporting events consistently price their tickets low enough that street scalpers risk jail time to hawk marked-up tickets, and StubHub makes hundreds of millions a year in revenue.</p></blockquote>

</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sci-Fi Suburbia</title>
      <link>/2013/08/28/sci-fi-suburbia.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 22:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <description><p><a href="http://www.theverge.com/2013/8/27/4664842/sweden-reimagined-what-if-sci-fi-tech-were-real">The Verge</a>:</p>




<blockquote><p>Robots and hovercrafts are commonplace, and decaying science facilities sprout from the harsh Scandinavian landscape.</p></blockquote>




<p>Incredible paintings by Swedish artist Simon Stålenhag.</p>

</description>
    </item>
    
 
  </channel>
</rss>